## **Artem Pakhomov**

### PHP Developer from Kyiv, Ukraine

Phone: +380 (50) 027-93-00 Email: setnemo@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/omentes

I have worked on the web industry for the last six years. I write a code according to SOLID, KISS, YAGNI, DRY. I publish all my pet projects on github as I adore open source. I am a backend developer and I fancy creating telegram bots. I began studying to play piano during the lockdown. This CV was created on PHP with Github Actions as I can't live without automation.



#### **Technologies**

PHP: OOP, SOLID, REST, TDD, PHPDoc, PSR, MVC, Composer, Laravel

 $\textbf{DB:} \ \mathsf{MySQL}, \ \mathsf{PostgreSQL}, \ \mathsf{Redis}$ 

Tests: PHPUnit, Codeception

Git: unserstand rebase, reflog, squash, cherry-pick, soft/hard reset, etc

Unix: used ArchLinux, Debian, MacOS, vim, grep, sed, ssh, etc

Containers: docker, k8s

Dev environment: nginx/docker, Postman, PHPStorm, xDebug

#### **Experience**

#### PHP Developer at Digitex Kyiv, Ukraine - 04/2021 - Present

- writing code with tests and documentation, working with queues, dockerize services, configure
  CI, etc
- implemented processes for developers, designers, managers via Jira for a team of 10-20 people.
  Process has flows for designing, developing, testing and releases

#### PHP Developer at airSlate Inc Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2019 - 04/2021

- writing code with tests and documentation, code review
- · deploy on dev/rc for testing, deploy release on prod
- create alert rules and checking the cause of alerts, working with metrics (tech and business)
- duty on burning issues

#### PHP Developer at Wallet Factory Kyiv, Ukraine - 01/2019 - 05/2019

- Back-end development for a Fin-tech mobile application.
- PHP 7+, OpenSSL, payments API integrations
- API integrations for sales/discounting etc

#### PHP Developer at MakeTop Kyiv, Ukraine - 05/2015 - 12/2018

- Implementation for search engine optimization
- Work with Opencart, Wordpress, etc.

#### Education

#### Software Architect UNIT Factory, Kyiv - 09/2017 - 11/2018

I am in the top 5 students of UNIT Factory (course 2017), I completed the 3 year program in 1 year. UNIT Factory StudHub. Volunteering in Exam. Event organization. Meet-up organization.

#### Pet projects

#### Repeat Word Bot https://t.me/RepeatWordBot

- Telegram bot to help you repeat new English words and learn pronunciation
- PHP, Doctrine, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, Github Actions

#### Currencies in UA Bot https://t.me/CurrencyUA\_bot

- Currency conversion inline for Ukraine
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Api integrations, Docker

#### Asterios RB bot https://github.com/omentes/asterios-bot

- Bot that helps players from Asterios Linage Server
- PHP, MySQL, Redis, Codeception, Docker, Github Actions

#### Cheatera https://cheatera.pp.ua

- Website statistics on students in UNIT Factory (Ecole 42)
- Consists of two subproject: filling the database with scripts on Python via cron, and a web site for viewing information written in php, Yii2.

#### **Publications**

#### Введение в метрики для РНР разработчика

https://habr.com/ru/post/544582/

Цель статьи познакомить читателя с принципами работы с метриками на php. В рамках статьи подготовлен готовый мини-проект в докер.

#### Рефакторинг пет проекта: докеризация, метрики, тесты

https://habr.com/ru/post/542978/

История как я рефакторил один из своих телеграм ботов, который из поделки на коленке стал сервисом с более чем 1000 пользователей в очень узкой и специфической аудитории.

#### Languages

- English Elementary proficiency
- Russian Native or bilingual proficiency
- Ukrainian Full professional proficiency

# Licenses & certifications

• Coursera: C++ Development Fundamentals: White Belt Link